Hello, I'm your host David Bernard and
with me today, Revenue Cat CEO Jacob
Heiding. Our guest today is Aura Levit,
VP of product management at LinkedIn,
where she leads revenue and product
teams focused on LinkedIn premium
subscriptions. On the podcast, we talked
with Aura about LinkedIn's valuedriven
growth philosophy, how they personalize
experiences and plan offerings based on
user intent and the complexity of
running over a thousand experiments a
year. Hey Orura, thanks so much for
joining us on the podcast today.
>> Thank you for having me. It's a pleasure
to be here.
>> And Jacob, nice to have you back on
after our bit of a hiatus with your busy
summer schedule and my busy schedule. I
just get owls in the window that tell me
I have to come to a sub club podcast and
it's it's been a while since we did had
one. So, I'm excited to to be here
today.
So, Aura, when you and I were talking
ahead of the podcast about potential
topics, one of the things you mentioned
to me is your approach to valuedriven
growth and the whole team thinking about
it in that way. And so, I think that's
really the best place to start this
podcast is what did you mean by
valuedriven growth? How do you think
about it? How do you talk about it
inside LinkedIn? And then I think that's
just a great framework for the rest of
the podcast talking about all the
different tactics and other topics.
>> For sure. Um so, uh within LinkedIn,
Premium uh offer solutions for consumers
and small businesses to help individuals
accelerate in their career, get
promoted, find a new job, build a
business, scale their business, find
leads, build their brand, and hire
people. And essentially uh what uh is
key for us is that we provide benefits
and value that helps members achieve
those tasks. There's many ways to drive
growth. For us, what was critical is to
make sure that we drive that growth by
helping our members achieve their jobs
to be done. And so, uh, within the last
two years, I want to say we added over
20 different benefits, uh, across
everything between helping you get
specific insights on how to get hired
and improve models that help you
understand on which jobs you're more
likely to hear back and how you match
and rank for that job. To uh, help with
making your profile stand out. From
adding a cover photo that rotates to
highlighting your achievements and
awards and recommendations from friends
to helping you fill your profile details
to dedicated events and learning courses
and a variety of other features that
ultimately help uh members get the job
that they're coming to us to get and pay
for get then. And our belief is that the
more value we provide and we explain to
members how they can use it and how it
helps them in their task they're trying
to achieve, the more likely they are to
come for that value and stay for that
value. And so we're growing both
acquisition and retention. And so a lot
of our growth was around that.
>> Does that play out in any kind of
specific processes inside LinkedIn? Like
do you have a default product spec where
there's a whole section on where the
product manager has to specifically say
this is the specific value and how
valuable we think it is or or how does
how does that play out in the day-to-day
kind of product decisions and and
experimentation and that sort of thing.
>> For sure. All our specs uh specify who
the member is that we're trying to
target with an offering and what's the
job to be done that we're trying to
solve for that member. there specific
use cases and specific member scenarios,
we would outline them and the specs um
would include that. But ultimately, it's
heavy focus on making sure that we're
growing value. And so we have a full
team that that's dedicated to the value
that our subscriptions are providing and
they're building new features and
enhancing adoption of features and
reaching the functionality of existing
features to ensure we continue growing
the value of those features. And that
team size is similar to the team that
drives growth from better pricing,
discovery, packaging, promotions, etc.
Because it's really the core uh of what
we do and how we operate.
>> People are pretty good if there's no
value, they'll stop paying, right? Or if
they've if they've reached their limit
of derived value, they'll just turn out.
So
>> yeah, I think for a lot of companies,
you know, who build value and they're
like, "Okay, it's great. Now let's go h
for growth." And then they forget that
the value is what bred them and they go
home and growth for many years. But
value is something that we believe needs
to continue to be delivered ongoingly
like you know the traditional product
life cycle. At some point you grow and
then you mature and you have to launch
new value to continue that growth trend
and disrupt it. And so what we're trying
to do is continuously launch more and
more value so that our users uh and
members always have an opportunity to
find what to come to LinkedIn for and
how to accomplish their jobs to be done
better through that value.
>> I think also people just get really used
to consumers get really used to whatever
they're doing, right? And so if if
there's not continuous novelty, right?
They're going to like look at the value
at even if something they valued at the
current price a year ago, right? if if
nothing has changed, um I always think
about this, it's sort of how you beat
inflation, right? You just keep adding
stuff to the product and then you can
hold your pricing, right? Um or or maybe
even increase it. But if you don't, you
know, yeah, it's purely extractive as
you were saying, you're eventually going
to extract all the value and then your
growth team and I I also just conjecture
if that's when growth teams get a bad
rap for like ruining products like
trying to extract all the growth, right?
Is if that's all you focus on, they will
you know what I mean? Like they will
drive features that actually aren't good
for the users. All they're doing is like
maximizing value extraction from my
perception as a LinkedIn user for as
long as I can remember. I don't know how
it's possible, but you're all still
adding stuff in 2025. And the numbers
like I was just I don't quote them here
so I don't drive your PR team mad, but
like your growth has been like better
than Facebook and and some axis and
stuff like this. So, which is kind of
surprising for a social network, right,
in in the year 2025. Um, and it must be
because of this, I would assume. Are are
there numbers that y'all share publicly?
>> LinkedIn has over a billion members. Uh
we have a healthy subscriber base. Our
subscription businesses are several
billion dollars of annual run rate.
>> Wow, that's incredible. And h how does
that valuedriven growth approach play
into the metrics you track and kind of
northstar metrics and like how you think
about you know what you look at day in
day out as you you know judge how the
business is moving.
>> Yeah. So we have a series of different
metrics. We look at uh how many members
we acquire, how well they retain with
the subscription between trial and paid
uh but also kind of throughout the
duration of their paid subscription. We
look at um what we call a premium
session which is a session in which a
premium member interacts with the
premium feature and we want more
essentially premium members to come more
frequently interact more and for us it's
a sign of value that they're arriving
for the product which is a sign that
they will continue staying with us for
the long term but overall we optimize as
a true north the business for long-term
revenue and I say long-term revenue not
short-term revenue because there's a lot
of revenue we forgo and don't want to
take because we believe it will squeeze
you know, the funnel in a way that we're
not interested in. And so we always
optimize for long-term longevity and we
believe that members pay with their
feet. If we would deliver value, they
would buy the product and if we continue
delivering on it, they will stay with
it.
It's so refreshing to hear this and and
I mean you would just I guess assume uh
such a mature company would operate this
way but so many folks in this industry
in the consumer subscription industry
don't and they are more extractive and
willing to you know make sacrifices they
just obsess about tactics right without
thinking about like the underlying
physics of the system you know which is
what this is describing that yeah and
the tactics are important right I'm sure
everything you all do on a micro basis
needs to be measured and done but like
if you if you forget about the big
picture eventually you know it'll lead
you to ruin. So
>> yeah subscription business are very
complex a lot of things that you do move
metrics in different direction. So you
have to remember what's the true north
and we made it easy for uh ourselves to
make the right decision by having
allocation for revenue we won't take
revenue that essentially is downside
because it's better for members and it's
better for as a result for us as a
business longterm and so we always
emphasize that we optimize for long-term
revenue.
>> Are there specific ways you measure that
long-term revenue like do you have a
predictive LTV model or how do you
actually measure that? Yeah, we do uh we
measure all ramps that we do, all
initiatives by analyzed bookings, which
is one year booking and then we model or
one year revenue and then we model
revenue for uh experiments that we
believe would change over time such as
pricing experiments and others on a
5-year horizon. And so we plot how that
would look over time because those
outcomes might change and make decision
based on the five-year view and not the
one-year view.
>> That makes sense. I mean, I was thinking
just I guess like from a premium
perspective on LinkedIn, your retention
may be varying, but the underlying user
retention of LinkedIn, I imagine
extremely high that I can't think of why
somebody would stop being a user
completely. They might go dormant for a
while if they're not like thinking about
it. But from a premium perspective, like
I would think even that like once
somebody uses some of the premium
features, they probably become very like
dependent on them and maybe you know
long term.
>> Yeah, we see a good relationship between
members. the more they use the link
LinkedIn, the more they're likely are to
sign up to premium because they want to
continue building their business or
accelerating their career, etc. And when
they sign up to premium, they're more
engaged with LinkedIn overall given the
value it provides. So, it's a nice
synergetic type of relationship. I think
you you either wrote a blog post about
this or or shared this one of the times
when we were speaking, but how does that
play into the product itself and like
where you put payw walls or like how you
highlight that value within the product
itself? because it feels like that's
such an important part that a lot of
people miss as well is if you have a
huge premium base, you know, part of
converting that premium base over time
is not annoying them, but then it's also
giving them opportunities to see that
extra value, to experience that extra
value. So, how does that play out in the
product itself?
>> So, first and foremost, LinkedIn's
mission is to provide an economic
opportunity for every member of the
global workforce. And that opportunity
is not paid. And so we prioritize our
free experiences first. That means that
anyone who comes to LinkedIn can build a
profile, can create content that will be
equally distributed in feed. They can
apply to jobs, they can glean any
information that uh is relevant for that
etc. And so that is really important for
us because that's our mission. LinkedIn
also has other businesses that provide
jobs on the platform etc. that also need
to ensure that uh we have an healthy
member base that engages in our
platform. The places where we um see
that we can provide additional paid
value are for example a feature that
might help you get additional leads. So
let's say uh you're selling books now
and you want to promote your website
that tells more about who you are and
sells that book. you have an opportunity
where you can add a link that says visit
my website or view my newsletter etc to
your profile that will also appear
anytime you post something in feed it
will be just below your name every time
you'll message someone it will be there
every time someone searches for you
they'll see it so it's everywhere and
it's a great opportunity for you to
promote your business that's something
that is needed for free value but it
helps you derive business outcomes and
it's something that we see our members
want to gain kind of leads from the
platform and provide It's an opportunity
for them to build their businesses. And
so that's an example of a feature that
we would make paid. Within the
experience, we often make uh features
premium. So we give a taste of a free
feature and then you can have an
enhanced functionality that's paid. For
example, on profile you have a cover
photo. Adding a cover photo is free. But
if you want to add rotating cover
photos, for example, to present your
work, portfolio, recommendations, other
things, adding multiple rotating cover
photos would be a paid functionality.
So, we try to make sure we have that
premium experiences wherever we can. And
I didn't even think about this until
just now and I didn't put it in my
notes, but it is fascinating too how
LinkedIn really is a two-sided
marketplace is that you do have the job
seekers and free users like we've been
talking about which you're incentivized
to maximize that number of users because
then you also sell to businesses who are
looking to hire. How does that even play
into all I I mean I imagine that's a
pretty complex balancing act of like you
said kind of keeping that premium
experience as strong as possible without
alienating that larger user base but
then also providing enough for both the
employer and the potential employee but
then also I mean I use it all the time
just because it's gotten really good for
for content.
>> That's exactly right. Threading that
needle uh is definitely something we
think about all the time, but for us
it's really important to make sure that
that free ecosystem thrives uh on the
platform to fulfill on our mission. And
like you said, we care about our
customers. Recruiters, hiring companies,
paying customers come to the platform to
ensure that they post jobs that job
seekers can find. And we want to make
sure that that value prop continues and
is strong. And so we wouldn't add
anything that would ever make something
that's related to uh finding a job or
applying to a job a paid functionality
want members to be able to find apply to
jobs etc. We would add features that
might help job seekers stand out and
would be beneficial for the recruiters
as well. For example, one of the premium
functionalities we have is the ability
to mark a job or up to three jobs a
month as your top choice. What you do by
doing that is saying this job is the job
I want the most and here's two sentence
elevator pitch on why I'm the best
candidate for that. On the recruiter
side we show you essentially this
candidate marked this job as a top
choice. Here's his like elevator pitch
essentially
>> creating like a artificial scarcity
right from a hirer perspective. I mean,
I'll tell you. I'll be like, "Well,
somebody burned I don't know how much it
costs, like 20 cents, a dollar, $5 being
me being their top job for the month."
Like, it's something, right? If they
can, if I know cuz as a hirer, like
you're always just afraid of people that
are just spraying and praying, right?
They're just applying to every job. They
don't care about you at all. You know,
it's just it's fine. I don't you know,
it's a numbers game at some point, but
like I would rather, you know, there's
tends to be better quality in the
candidates that actually picked you for
a reason, right? Um and so that's a
great feature.
>> Yeah. No, 100%. We see that members uh
value from that feature to a great
extent. Essentially, we launched it I
think about a year and a half or two ago
and we see that individuals who do
choose a job as our top choice are 46%
more likely to hear back from the
recruiter. So,
>> yeah, it doesn't surprise me. That
sounds about right. Yeah. Yeah. Where I
mean, we're just always looking for some
sort of standout signal, right? there's
so much I mean I guess maybe the the
flip side of of LinkedIn creating such
liquidity is that is that sometimes it's
created too much liquidity where there's
too much access right but I think that's
what you need you know I it's fascin I
never thought of LinkedIn as really a
two-sided marketplace but it is but less
so than like Airbnb or like I don't
think of Facebook as a two-sided
marketplace right like I think of it as
sort of like a one-sided marketplace
where everybody posts everybody consumes
equally like there's no there's only one
class but LinkedIn's interesting because
it's like I guess anybody in there can
be potentially either, right? And they
go back and forth from being on the
supply side and the demand side when
they're between jobs and things like
this, which is really interesting. It
has to create, you know, I I haven't
snuck it in yet, but I would love to
we're getting we're talking about it,
but working on LinkedIn just has to be
such an incredible challenge from the
like surface area perspective, right?
Because you just have so many things in
LinkedIn and so much history, you know,
when it comes to AB testing. As you're
saying, like subscription products are
complex. I have to think that LinkedIn
is uniquely complex. It's a fascinating
perspective though in thinking through
what features to make premium, how to
make them premium, like how to balance
the value. Uh we we did a podcast with
somebody who was at Tinder in the early
days and it actually reminds me a lot of
that. And the way he put it is that you
don't want to add features, especially
like as consumables as they did with
Tinder, that like break the game. So you
you wouldn't want features that make it
where people wouldn't want to apply to a
job, but being able to stand out a
little extra is kind of like the the
super boosts and some of the other
things that Tinder sells as consumables.
And so it's fascinating even kind of the
the game theory of it all of and I think
you know to the to the average
subscription app thinking through it in
these ways of like what features are
valuable but we want to actually keep
them behind the payw wall but then how
do we enhance that feature in a way that
you know can be enhanced if you are a
prouser like getting those things right
is such a key part of building a truly
great subscription business. So even if
you're not LinkedIn and you're listening
to this podcast, like the ideas here can
apply in so many different ways. And so
it's fascinating to kind of hear how
you're thinking about it.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Um I think it's true
for all subscriptions. Ultimately, if
you're living in an ecosystem that has a
free component and a paid component,
continue to growing your free ecosystem
and top of funnel is, you know, what's
going to help your paid ecosystem as
well grow over time. And you have to
always balance the two. And if you break
that balance, it will obviously, you
know, pull the ecosystem in a certain
direction that you might want or not.
And so it's very important to be
thoughtful about those decisions.
>> How does all this play out in testing?
Because I know, you know, you and the
team there at LinkedIn, there's a
culture of testing, of wanting to try
lots of things, and you know, huge team
now and a lot of users to experiment on.
So I'd love to start diving into testing
and and at the highest level like how
does that valuedriven growth shape how
you do the testing
>> within the premium team alone by our
LinkedIn it would be a lot higher but
within our premium subscriptions we run
over a thousand AB tests a year we
essentially test anything that we would
launch into market uh whether it's a new
feature a new layout a new way to talk
about kind of the value that we provide
it would all go through an AB test
process where we would evaluate what
resonates better for our members.
Ultimately I don't believe in you know
the sitting in office just ourselves and
figuring out what it should be because
we have millions of members they know
better what works for them and so the
more we can minimize you know time
internally and maximize time where we
learn and go to market and get that
signal the better we are at serving our
customers and so that's kind of how we
go about things. We have uh on our team
a very bottoms updriven AB testing
culture. Each product manager owns a
certain area or domain and they work
towards growing that area and so they
run their tests and make sure that they
kind of reach uh the goals and the road
map that they set and we try to go for
forward momentum and so the more we go
uh and try and test the faster we get to
delivering more value to members. I
would definitely say there are some
sacred things um in sense of we wouldn't
want to put an experience that we're not
proud of in front of members or on our
feed, right? We wouldn't want to put
something that is disruptive that we
feel like members won't enjoy.
>> And so those would be things that we
just often just not even discuss, not
consider, not launch. And sometimes if
the debate would come of it has a
business subset or opportunity, we would
lean on the member side. We talk with,
you know, what is best for the member
long term. I think generally my personal
approach is we gain more insights
testing over debating when you know we
all feel that the experience is worth
testing and so I try to spend less time
on debates and reviews and more time on
speed than iteration and learning from
customers
>> and how do you think about different
users getting different experiences? I
have a lot of people ask me like when
I've done office hours in the past or
just you know talking to other
subscription app practitioners
especially at LinkedIn where it might
make the news that you've rolled out a
new feature you know and some people are
seeing the feature and some people
aren't maybe some people are seeing one
price or one opportunity that other
people's aren't h how do you think about
with such a large user base offering
those different experiences in I would
assume smaller subsets as you're testing
and yeah how do you think about that
>> yeah I think ultimately every test
ultimately either will ramp or they ramp
so if it's successful you know it will
ramp for members and if it's not
successful it won't and it's our way to
understand what works for members best
as fast as we can also know that members
have different needs if you're a member
who's coming from Italy and you're in
the food industry you have different
desires and needs from someone who works
in accounting in New or someone who is a
small business owner uh in Brazil. And
so we want to make sure that our
experiences are customized and are
localized and are relevant for what you
do and what you're looking from us to
do. Um essentially if you're jobseeking,
it's very different and you're trying to
grow your business. So we don't want to
bombard you with things that are
irrelevant for you. And so we try to
tailor and customize and personalize the
experience the best we can for what we
think would be valuable for you. We
haven't uh found downsides so far to it.
Usually the downside is from not doing
enough personalization. Every time we
tailor the experience more, we make it
more relevant. Our members find more
value in it. And so that's an ever
growing effort.
>> How do you even just manage a thousand
tests per year? Cuz that's like three
plus a day. Is there like a single air
traffic controller that's like making
sure these aren't conflicting or do you
just send it and just you know you'll
hear back if it did something bad
between I'm talking like cross you know
or or maybe you have them all isolated
because you have so many users maybe you
can just you can keep it all isolated.
Is there like Yeah. What is that process
like as a growth product team?
>> Yeah we have a system that measures how
every experiment does it does uh look to
the bias experiment overlaps. we do at
time sequence things um and so if we
know that two things might clash and mix
each other's reads in some way that we
can't disentangle we would stagger
things sometimes you know our tech would
also demand some type of sequencing and
so we do do those things but ultimately
we operate across a large ecosystem that
has many surfaces and many members
>> and many experiments don't need that
sequence
>> right I guess that's the that's the flip
side benefit benefit of the complexity
of LinkedIn as a product, right? Is you
have all these different somewhat
isolated places you can test and and
they'll and they can they can be done
independently. I'm just thinking that's
like three tests a day. Like that's a
lot more. Yes.
>> Yeah. That's that's that's only working
days. So it's more than three tests per
day probably which is just it's crazy.
It's incredible.
>> You mentioned personalization and I know
one of the things you do personalize is
which plans you offer to a user. Yeah.
I'd love for you to dig more into how
that personalization plays out in the
product itself, but then also in those
like premium experiences and the plans
you offer and things like that.
>> Yeah. So, we ask when you kind of come
to our float saying you're interested in
premium, uh we ask if you're looking for
a job or if you're looking to grow your
business or to hire or something else.
Based on your answer, uh we then decide
what type of content to show you. Often
times we also know because we saw that
you just searched for a job and so
you're looking for that job and so we
try to do the best that we can to match
what you're looking for by your actions
and the input that you provided us to
the experience that we show you so that
it's relevant because ultimately if it's
not you'll be like okay you guys totally
don't get me what I'm looking to do here
this is not for me then you'll be right
to do so and so making sure that it's
relevant is a key for us
>> I would imagine a lot of driven by
machine learning and so but I'd love to
hear if um you know because it's such a
hot topic these days but have generative
LLM
been useful at all in that or is it
primarily driven by more kind of machine
learning model kind of algorithms on the
back end
>> we have both um we do use machine
learning and AI quite extensively in
terms of LLMs we offer u value prep such
as let us help you edit your profile for
example you want to write a summary you
know how to write. A big thing members
tell us is I have this writer's block. I
look at it, it's empty. I don't know how
what to say about myself. Like, how
would you describe me? And so, we're
like, no problem. Here's three options
of how we would describe you based on
your, you know, profile data and where
you worked and you can edit it. We would
like you to edit it to sound in your
voice. We allow you to make it shorter,
longer, more professional, less
professional. you know, uh there's
different options, but that is an
example of LLM coming for help to solve
a problem like that.
>> So, you're using LLM's more on the
consumerf facing side to help the
customers. And I I'm still trying to
sort out in my own mind all the
different things LLMs are actually
helpful for. but as this like magic box
you throw into stuff stuff into and get
stuff out. I'm just was wondering if
there was any specific things in
personalization and otherwise that it is
helpful for or if you are still
primarily using machine learning for
those kind of personalizations.
we are uh moving to have a limb based
personalization algorithms and so a lot
of the transitions that you see on
LinkedIn today in terms of how we help
you search and find for jobs etc are
moving into being more LLM empowered and
so it's somewhat of an evolution right
of our machine learning algorithms and
the goal is the same to find better more
relevant answers and experiences for our
members
>> I chat with chat with my business
network, you know, be like, who do I
know that's going to help me, you know,
achieve this thing and it's going to go
through and it's going to tell me who to
who to bug, who who to mail.
>> That's a we provide your recommendations
for that.
>> Yeah. Do you Oh, yeah. What to write?
Yeah.
>> I'll be using LinkedIn this week to um
so we're we're hosting Appgrowth annual
our annual conference in New York City
uh in October. And one of the things I
have found it tremendously useful for is
um you know sorting all of my
connections by who is in the New York
area or even the east coast and then hey
let me stop by your office or meet up or
make sure they get an a personal invite
or things like that. But yeah, I could
see it being super useful for things
like that as well of like using LLMs to
actually sort through your vast network
of like when when you have a specific
>> the the the advanced search in
LinkedIn's pretty good, but sometimes
I'm looking for something super wonky
like I need somebody to do a back
channel and this person used to work at
this company three companies ago D and I
could see like a really well hooked up
rag search and stuff like that could
probably help me do that much faster.
Sometimes I struggle with some of the
LinkedIn filters and stuff like this.
Um, but anyway, you can take that back
to your product team.
>> I'm enjoying.
>> Nice. Um, so you've already talked a bit
about retention in the context of that
long-term value being your north star,
but what are some of the tactics and
other ways that you think about
retaining users over time and
incentivizing that retention?
>> Yeah, so we look a lot uh into what type
of value and benefits we provide that
members retain better after using. For
example, if members are more likely to
hear back from recruiters, they're more
likely to retain. And so we try to
provide more value props to address
that. We say that articulating the value
also helps if we do a better job at
telling you what benefits we have and
how to use them. Those type of messaging
changes alone uh would improve retention
because our members are better informed
and know what and how to use the
product. And so that has been a driver.
And then we provide economic benefits uh
to individuals who are looking to stay
with us for the long term. So for
example, if you want to take an annual
plan with premium you will get uh a
significant discount towards that. And
that's also a great economic you know
opportunity for you. We been testing and
dual plans that allow you to take a plan
for you and a family, friend, partner,
spouse, colleague etc. And then we also
provide 20% discount for you taking kind
of two plans. And so we see that those
type of offers uh have also better
retention whether because there's a
social effect of you know you and a
friend interacting with it or because we
provide greater value for a lower price
since you stayed with us for a year etc.
and you're more likely to see that value
and stay for a second and third and four
year and we have customers who have been
with us for over a decade. One concept
you you mentioned to me was uh
boomerang. And I never heard that term
before, but I I'd like to use this
podcast to help socialize that term.
>> Well, David, it's a it's a throwing
instrument that they use in Australia.
Sorry. See, that's what that's the value
I bring to the podcast.
>> But, uh, boomerang being users who
canled but came back. Tell tell me more
about what that means and how how you
think about that in LinkedIn.
>> Yeah. So, um, as your subscription
grows, you see more of your members who
tried you at some point come back. Uh,
that's a good sign. Uh, it means that,
you know, they got the value at some
point in time. For whatever reason, they
decided they're not going to use premium
uh, for the short term, but then they
came back later. Sometimes it can be
because they're looking for a job again
and they're looking for something to
help them with that specific job search.
Sometimes it can be because they're
starting a business. different reasons
for different seasons in life.
Ultimately for us, I would want everyone
to stay with us. But if you leave for
whatever reason, I want to make sure
that you know you got the value, you
left us happy so that you come back at a
later point. And what we've seen is that
as we've grown, a much larger portion of
our ccentives became boomerangs. And
today they're just a big population that
we see, you know, comes back to use our
products and resubscribes. We're happy
to have them.
How do you incentivize that? Are there
specific like win back offers or other
things or or and and do you even kind of
segment that by maybe demonstrated
intent? So the people who come back and
are high intent, maybe you don't offer a
discount and maybe folks who come back
and are there but seem lower intent, do
you offer a bigger discount or how how
does that work on the kind of win back
and financial offer side? Yeah. So, we
do use um whether you've been a
subscriber before to understand how
likely you are to subscribe again. Uh
which would indicate what type of
experiences you see and what type of
messaging you would see because we do
see that you're more likely to
resubscribe. Uh we have at times offers
that are around winbacks and specific
promotions for boomerangs. We do look at
different signals to decide if and when
to offer those. Generally, our
subscription is we're not a high
discount subscription. So, it's not the
type of thing where you search online
and you find a coupon code and redeem
it. It's our price is our price. Uh you
can get a great discount if you want to
take an annual plan. We do use uh AI
algorithms at times decide on offers
such as boomerang, ringbacks, um etc.
But those depend on the use case.
One of the tactics that I've seen
implemented in LinkedIn, I think has
been talked about, maybe you even wrote
a post on LinkedIn about this that I
read, reoffering trials, which a lot of
folks don't do. And in, you know, the
app stores actually specifically prevent
people from using a free trial after
they've used a free trial. And so if
it's in the app store specifically, if
it if you give them the same product, uh
if you display the same product, it
doesn't matter if it was 10 years ago
that they used your free trial, they
don't get the option for a free trial.
But at LinkedIn, you do offer free
trial. So I'm curious like why you do
that and then what that actually looks
like and how you determine when and who
gets that secondary free trial offer.
>> Yeah, that's actually an area we're
testing with right now. Essentially,
our offering changes over time. And so,
as I mentioned, we believe in
value-driven growth. We add a lot of
value. And so, the premium that you've
seen if you subscribe 2 years ago is not
the premium today. It's a very different
product. And I want you to try it out.
And so, um, even if you were a P
subscriber, I might offer a free trial
again. Usually, we would do it with not
within the first 12 months. So, if you
tried LinkedIn for free in the last 12
months, it will be paid. But after that
we do experiment and test right now with
different scenarios of when and how uh
we would offer uh that free trial. But
we have been generous generally allowing
members to taste premium whether it's
for uh free no trial needed uh in our
premium experiences uh or via trials.
It's really fascinating and probably
something more uh subscription apps
should and will experiment with over
time as their user bases mature, as
their products mature. I mean, I could
definitely see some of these bigger apps
that have been around a long time could
drive a lot of growth by going back to
some of those early cohorts who got a
much worse experience a year ago, two
years ago, 5 years ago, and offer him
another free trial. So, it's it's really
cool to see LinkedIn doing that and uh
and seeing success with it at scale. Um,
so another another thing for people to
take away from this and go try.
>> It's silly like the app stores. I I
don't even think now with intro offers
and stuff that you can even do it,
right? I guess maybe with winback offers
on iOS you can um
>> you'd have to use offers. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. But it's a pain. Like that's
a lot of work, right? But it's the
default the mechanism you just burn a
free trial once. um the reactivation and
the boomerang thing. Again, it goes back
to the the value creation loop thing. If
you're building good stuff, like, you
know, talk to your users that have left
because they might come back just for
the new stuff, right?
>> Yeah. It's a great win back tactic, too,
of of folks who have been around and,
you know, they haven't experienced the
product for a year. The win back is,
hey, look at these five really awesome
things that you probably would want that
weren't in the product when you last
engaged with the product. And speaking
of adding value, I know you know you've
already talked about um adding value
with AI and some of the experiments
there, but are there other places
specifically where AI has allowed you to
add a lot of value to the product? I
think we're now experimenting with
products for small businesses and so
areas that help them grow, find
prospect, find leads essentially, uh
help them uh with building their brand
are areas that we're leaning into. We
have solutions that allow individuals to
hire online and so it helps them to
draft a compelling job description which
is a tedious process. we better rank
individuals who are fit for the job for
you as a hireer. So there's many areas
where AI has changed the experience and
in a way that save time uh and work and
money to help you get to where you need
to. So that's what we're trying to do.
find more opportunities to make it
simpler, automate, save time, you know,
make it valuable because we know that
especially as small business owners,
you're short on time, you're short on
resources. You don't necessarily have a
ton of,
>> you know, individuals that you can hire
to run a big team with uh expertise that
are very domain specific and so we try
to take the work from you and work for
you. And so that's what I allowed us to
do. LinkedIn might have been the first
ones to have the like AI generated
comments turned on. Do you know like
when you go into a comment and it was
like here's some options to say? I think
that LinkedIn might have been one of the
first people to be like you know what
>> you could just let AI write this for
you. And I I would bet that drove a lot
of engagement. It would be my guess.
>> So the AI suggestions are uh short for
comments specifically. They're more
around letting you drive the lead.
They're not full drafts. um it's more
around you know getting you to start
engaging and giving you an idea of how
you can contribute and what you can say
and how you can start a discussion
because ultimately LinkedIn is about
finding opportunity and that's
facilitated by a network when you create
when you comment that indicates to the
visual that you're interested in what
they have to say they then might be more
interested in continuing conversation
even if they don't know you comment you
can connect you can start messaging and
you can start having your relationship
which is a much natural way than uh
approaching someone you don't know on
the street etc. And so we give those
tools we allow you to build your brand
find those opportunities to contribute
and we encourage you to participate and
create those human connections
ultimately to help you get to where you
want to go.
>> How do you position those kind of
features within LinkedIn? I I feel like
I mean I visit LinkedIn pretty much
every day, but I'm not a job seeker and
I'm I'm not part of the like recruiting
and screening team, so I'm not using it
as an employer either. But I don't feel
like I see like AI like magic like
little AI icon, you know, like a lot of
companies seem to be positioning it that
way of like, you know, work faster with
AI. So maybe I just haven't seen it
because I'm not in the segment where
you're doing that. But I'm curious if
you are specifically promoting it as AI
or just as like helpful tools because it
sounds like you maybe most of these
things are just more positioned as like
move faster, you know, better product
versus like magic AI.
>> You don't come to LinkedIn for AI and
the magic of AI is a bit tubicous,
right? Like what what is AI really? And
so you come to LinkedIn to keep in touch
with your network, to gain professional
knowledge, to understand how you can do
your job better, keep in touch with the
news and the trends and what's happening
in your industry and in your local. And
we want to facilitate that and AI helps
us do that. And if you're a small
business owner, it helps us give you the
tools to grow your business. If you are
a job seeker, it helps us help you find
a job. But you come for that. You don't
come for AI. And so the goal is not to
sprinkle AI everywhere and say we're
here. AI is us. Like what does that
really mean for a human, right? And so
I'm here to first help you with what
you're trying to do. And AI is a way for
me to do that when it's for, you know,
applicable and helpful.
>> That that's such a great perspective.
And I and I think a great perspective
for a lot of folks trying to figure out
how to, you know, sell it, how to
actually integrate it into their own
products of of like keep that north
star, the north star there. I love that
they're not people aren't coming to
LinkedIn for AI. They're coming to
LinkedIn for a very specific job to be
done or range of jobs to be done and
focus your AI efforts around that versus
just sprinkling the magic everywhere and
telling people it's magic.
>> It's why we never made the sparkle team
or the sparkle squad at revenue count. I
wanted to start a team called the
sparkle squad and it got shut down for
that reason. Smarter people prevailed.
>> One of the other things y'all did
recently was partnering with notion and
the idea of bundling is such a
fascinating thing with subscriptions
because if you are able to kind of like
you said with the family plan if you
know if you're getting additional value
through your subscription you're more
likely to retain. So tell me about the
notion deal or any other partnership
programs that you have that you use to
add value to your product.
>> Yeah. Uh so we have partners that we
work with. Um you can see them if you're
a premium member. You can go to your uh
premium benefits dashboard and there's a
perks kind of offering there. Uh and we
have uh several different types of
partnerships. One of them is rotating
partnerships that we provide on a around
a monthly basis such as you can now get
access to notion with AI for 6 months
which is a great offering for our
audience. you know that type of product
is helpful for uh we also offer more of
a green uh perks that we also uh rotate
but in a less frequency um and so that
would be access to Dualingo or
Washington Journal or other benefits and
for us it's a way to give more value
back to our members we definitely try to
provide that when we can
>> and do you see engagement with those
perks as a signal for better retention
>> yeah we definitely ly see that uh
members who generally use our features
more and get to know premium better stay
for the value. They want to see what
additional perks we have. We refresh
them every 6 to 12 months. They want to
see the monthly rotating perk. We now
have 3 months with Spotify for three and
four months of Headspace. And so, you
know, there's a variety of uh offerings.
I mentioned 3 months of Dolingo. There's
coaching and whatnot. And so, uh, if you
get more out of the subscription, you're
more likely, um, ultimately to see this
value and stay with us.
>> Yeah, that's great. The last thing I
wanted to talk about was industry
learnings. So, when I think about a
company like LinkedIn, I think, oh, you
know, with billion plus users and like,
you know, one of the largest
subscription products in the world, it
feels like you're operating on such a
different plane that you wouldn't have
anything to learn. But I was incredibly
flattered to hear that you'd actually
listened to a Sub Club podcast. But I'
I' I'd love to hear like how you
approach learning from the rest of the
industry, you know, as a team that is
operating on a whole different
>> Yeah.
>> Most people don't have the capability to
push a thousand tests a year. I just
don't know if you know that. That's
really not, you know, we don't have the
same tools.
>> Yeah. Well, first I think the
subscription space uh is fascinating and
it's different. Every company out there
is doing something else and we know only
what's in our four walls. We don't know
what happens out there and what other
great companies are learning and we can
accelerate that learning speed and time.
Uh if you better understand, you know,
if there's best practices that we can
leverage and so there's multiple ways
where we do that. I review earning
reports uh of all the big subscriptions
out there at least twice a year
frequently more often. I actually write
summaries of those. So if you visited my
profile on LinkedIn, you can see
summaries of the state of the
subscription based on earning reports
and there's trends you can see that
subscriptions find success in um and
then lean into and we learn from that.
It's a good opportunity for us also to
understand who's innovating in what
sense and what we can bring for our
members as well. uh we also have
knowledge sharing conversations with uh
my peers in the industry and other
companies. I share what works for us in
a more closed you know private forum.
they share what works for them and it
helps both of our sides you know lead
our teams um in the right directions and
gain additional learnings and so we we
have those ties across the industry you
know I'm always looking for more so if
there's an individuals who are listening
to that podcast and would like to share
notes I would love to do that and I also
listen to as much information as I can
get um and that includes your podcast
that includes audio books and other
avenues to understand better and make
sure that uh I do the best I can for our
members every day.
>> That's so great and uh cool to hear and
and great to have you on the podcast,
too. And and we'll wrap up on this, but
you know, I've really enjoyed hosting
this podcast and being able to talk to
folks like you who are willing to just
share like what's working, what's not.
And so, so it's great that LinkedIn
would allow you to do this that you were
so open to share, you know, what's
working, what's not, and the kind of
tests you're running and those kind of
things. So, it is pretty cool. Well, it
feels like as an industry we are pretty
open to to sharing and so that is a cool
thing and then great to hear that you
know you're taking lessons from things
other people are sharing and you know
helping to grow.
>> I mean I know sometimes you can catch
stuff that's not in the gap numbers that
you can't see on like Yahoo Finance or
whatever right and they'll talk about
churn and they'll talk about some of
those things for a lot of the big
consumer whatever subscriptions. Um I
was like we should do that David more
like on our content like we just it's a
scale we don't really think about um but
maybe we should right you know dream
>> big yeah there's earning calls and
transcripts where you can hear directly
from the CEO CFO cos and what works for
them and you can gain a lot of great
knowledge from that uh you can use to
summarize it but I I like to read I like
to to feel the sentiment and understand
kind of between the lines knowing the
industry well and so I recommend it to
everyone for sure. Is there anything
else you wanted to share as we're
wrapping up? I think for us it's u we
believe LinkedIn premium is a great
product for everyone who's looking to
advance in their career whether it's
gain additional knowledge through
learning courses through additional
skills understanding how to use AI to
finding a new job to just building a
brand staying connected staying in touch
with your network you know if you're
building a business they're a great
solution as well and I actually can't
think of a you know individual in the
workforce who would not find value in
the offerings that we have today. So, I
highly would love your listeners to try
Premium out and hopefully we meet what
you're looking for.
>> Me, just hustling for growth in every
corner. I love it. Uh,
thank you so much for joining us. This
was such a fascinating conversation. I
really appreciate it.
>> Thank you for having me.
>> Thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute, please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by chat.sub. subclub.com to
join our private community.
[Music]